<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title> =^..^= MEH</title><link>https://chowy1026.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="https://chowy1026.github.io/rss.xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 03:42:53 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Lolita - Vladimir Nabokov</title><link>https://chowy1026.github.io/books/lolita/</link><dc:creator>cHoWy</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Quotes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Human life is but a series of footnotes to a vast obscure unfinished masterpiece"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"He broke my heart. You merely broke my life."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"It was love at first sight, at last sight, at ever and ever sight."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"I knew I had fallen in love with Lolita forever; but I also knew she would not be forever Lolita."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"You have to be an artist and a madman, a creature of infinite melancholy, with a bubble of hot poison in your loins and a super-voluptuous flame permanently aglow in your subtle spine (oh, how you have to cringe and hide!), in order to discern at once, by ineffable signs―the slightly feline outline of a cheekbone, the slenderness of a downy limbs, and other indices which despair and shame and tears of tenderness forbid me to tabulate―the little deadly demon among the wholesome children; she stands unrecognized by them and unconscious herself of her fantastic power."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“I recall certain moments, let us call them icebergs in paradise, when after having had my fill of her –after fabulous, insane exertions that left me limp and azure-barred–I would gather her in my arms with, at last, a mute moan of human tenderness (her skin glistening in the neon light coming from the paved court through the slits in the blind, her soot-black lashes matted, her grave gray eyes more vacant than ever–for all the world a little patient still in the confusion of a drug after a major operation)–and the tenderness would deepen to shame and despair, and I would lull and rock my lone light Lolita in my marble arms, and moan in her warm hair, and caress her at random and mutely ask her blessing, and at the peak of this human agonized selfless tenderness (with my soul actually hanging around her naked body and ready to repent), all at once, ironically, horribly, lust would swell again–and 'oh, no,' Lolita would say with a sigh to heaven, and the next moment the tenderness and the azure–all would be shattered.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"if a violin string could ache, i would be that string."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Lolita, light of my life, fire of my loins. My sin, my soul. Lo-lee-ta: the tip of the tongue taking a trip of three steps down the palate to tap, at three, on the teeth. Lo. Lee. Ta. She was Lo, plain Lo, in the morning, standing four feet ten in one sock. She was Lola in slacks. She was Dolly at school. She was Dolores on the dotted line. But in my arms she was always Lolita. "&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“You know, what's so dreadful about dying is that you are completely on your own. and it struck me, as my automaton knees went up and down, that I simply did not know a thing about my darling's mind and that quite possibly, behind the awful juvenile cliches, there was in her a garden and a twilight, and a palace gate - dim and adorable regions which happened to be lucidly and absolutely forbidden to me, in my polluted rags and miserable convulsions...”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Don't touch me; I'll die if you touch me.”  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Despite our tiffs, despite her nastiness, despite all the fuss and faces she made, and the vulgarity, and the danger, and the horrible hopelessness of it all, I still dwelled deep in my elected paradise - a paradise whose skies were the color of hell-flames - but still a paradise.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“In a nervous and slender-leaved mimosa grove at the back of their villa we found a perch on the ruins of a low stone wall. She trembled and twitched as I kissed the corner of her parted lips and the hot lobe of her ear. A cluster of stars palely glowed above us between the silhouettes of long thin leaves; that vibrant sky seemed as naked as she was under her light frock. I saw her face in the sky, strangely distinct, as if it emitted a faint radiance of its own. Her legs, her lovely live legs, were not too close together, and when my hand located what it sought, a dreamy and eerie expression, half-pleasure, half-pain, came over those childish features. She sat a little higher than I, and whenever in her solitary ecstasy she was led to kiss me, her head would bend with a sleepy, soft, drooping movement that was almost woeful, and her bare knees caught and compressed my wrist, and slackened again; and her quivering mouth, distorted by the acridity of some mysterious potion, with a sibilant intake of breath came near to my face. She would try to relieve the pain of love by first roughly rubbing her dry lips against mine; then my darling would draw away with a nervous toss of her hair, and then again come darkly near and let me feed on her open mouth, while with a generosity that was ready to offer her everything, my heart, my throat, my entrails, I gave her to hold in her awkward fist the scepter of my passion.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Poem Wanted, Wanted&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wanted, wanted: Dolores Haze.
Hair: brown. Lips: scarlet.
Age: five thousand three hundred days.
Profession: none, or "starlet"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where are you hiding, Dolores Haze?
Why are you hiding, darling?
(I Talk in a daze, I walk in a maze
I cannot get out, said the starling).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where are you riding, Dolores Haze?
What make is the magic carpet?
Is a Cream Cougar the present craze?
And where are you parked, my car pet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who is your hero, Dolores Haze?
Still one of those blue-capped star-men?
Oh the balmy days and the palmy bays,
And the cars, and the bars, my Carmen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh Dolores, that juke-box hurts!
Are you still dancin', darlin'?
(Both in worn levis, both in torn T-shirts,
And I, in my corner, snarlin').&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy, happy is gnarled McFate
Touring the States with a child wife,
Plowing his Molly in every State
Among the protected wild life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Dolly, my folly! Her eyes were vair,
And never closed when I kissed her.
Know an old perfume called Soliel Vert?
Are you from Paris, mister?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L'autre soir un air froid d'opera m'alita;
Son fele -- bien fol est qui s'y fie!
Il neige, le decor s'ecroule, Lolita!
Lolita, qu'ai-je fait de ta vie?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dying, dying, Lolita Haze,
Of hate and remorse, I'm dying.
And again my hairy fist I raise,
And again I hear you crying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officer, officer, there they go--
In the rain, where that lighted store is!
And her socks are white, and I love her so,
And her name is Haze, Dolores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officer, officer, there they are--
Dolores Haze and her lover!
Whip out your gun and follow that car.
Now tumble out and take cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wanted, wanted: Dolores Haze.
Her dream-gray gaze never flinches.
Ninety pounds is all she weighs
With a height of sixty inches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My car is limping, Dolores Haze,
And the last long lap is the hardest,
And I shall be dumped where the weed decays,
And the rest is rust and stardust.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>book</category><category>Vladimir Nabokov</category><guid>https://chowy1026.github.io/books/lolita/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 03:10:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Helpful Links on Nikola</title><link>https://chowy1026.github.io/links/nikola/</link><dc:creator>cHoWy</dc:creator><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://getnikola.com/" title="Nikola Homepage"&gt;Nikola Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://nikola.readthedocs.io/en/latest/" title="Nikola Documentation"&gt;Nikola Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/nikola-discuss" title="Nikola Google Group"&gt;Nikola Google Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/getnikola/nikola" title="Nikola Github"&gt;Nikola Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://nikola.readthedocs.io/en/latest/creating-a-theme/" title="Theming Nikola"&gt;Theming Nikola&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://nikola.readthedocs.io/en/latest/manual/#math" title="MathJax on Nikola"&gt;MathJax on Nikola&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://sampathweb.com/posts/blogging-made-easy.html" title="GitHub DEPLOY_COMMANDS in Config.py"&gt;GitHub DEPLOY_COMMANDS in Config.py&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>helpful-links</category><category>Nikola</category><guid>https://chowy1026.github.io/links/nikola/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 02:31:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Descriptive Statistics - Lesson 1</title><link>https://chowy1026.github.io/course-notes/descriptive-statistics/lesson-1/</link><dc:creator>cHoWy</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Lesson 1: Introduction to Research Methods&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Some Definitions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constructs**&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contruct&lt;/strong&gt;: Anything that is difficult to measure because it can be defined and measured in very many different ways.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operational Definition&lt;/strong&gt;: Operational Definitions {of a construct} is a unit of measurement for a construct.  Once an Operational Definitions is defined {for a construct}, it is no longer a construct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extraneous Factors&lt;/strong&gt;: Also known as "Lurking Variables", these factors that could impact the outcome of an experiment or test.  Extraneous factors should be held constant as much as possible to maximize accuracy of experiments/tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;!-- For mathJax, use \\( xxx \\) for inline; \\[ xxx \\] for block --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samples and Populations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Population Parameter&lt;/strong&gt;: denoted by \(  \mu \) (μ pronounced mu) are values that describe the whole population.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sample statistics&lt;/strong&gt;: denoted by \( \overline{x} \) (pronounced as X-bar) are values that describe our sample.  Statistics are used to estimate/approximate the population parameter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sampling Error&lt;/strong&gt;: The difference of values between true population parameter and sample statistics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sample Size&lt;/strong&gt;: The size of the group that we choose to represent population.  The bigger the sample size, the smaller the sampling error generally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Golden Arches Theory {of Conflict Prevention} by Thomas Friedman&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correlations doesn't mean causation: Just because two variables are relatable, it doesn't mean once causes the other to occur.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experiments vs Observational Studies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To show relationships =&amp;gt; Perform observational studies i.e. surveys.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(+) Easy way to get information of a population,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(+) Relatively inexpensive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(+) Can be conducted remotely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(+) Anyone could access and analyze survey results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(-) Untruthful responses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(-) Biased responses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(-) Respondents not understanding the questions (Response Bias)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(-) Respondents refuse to answer (Non-response Bias)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To show causation =&amp;gt; Perform controlled experiments i.e.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other Definitions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treatments&lt;/strong&gt;: The manner in which researchers handle subjects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Observational Studies&lt;/strong&gt;: When an experimenter watches a group of subjects and does not introduce a treatment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Independent Variables&lt;/strong&gt;: The variable that the experimenter chooses to manipulate, usually plotted along x-axis on a graph.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dependent Variables&lt;/strong&gt;: The variable that the experimenter chooses to measure, usually plotted along y-axis on a graph.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treatment Group&lt;/strong&gt;: The group of a study that receives a varying levels of independent variable, used to measure the effect of a treatment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control Group&lt;/strong&gt;: The group of study that doesn't receive treatment, used as a baseline when compared to treatment groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Placebo&lt;/strong&gt;: Something that is given to the control group so they think they are getting the treatment, when in reality it causes no effect on them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blinding&lt;/strong&gt;: A technique used to reduce bias, i.e. placebo is blinding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Double Blinding&lt;/strong&gt;: A technique to ensure those who administer treatments and those receiving treatments do not know who is actually receiving which treatment.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controlled Factors&lt;/strong&gt;: Factors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Random Assignments&lt;/strong&gt;: A technique used to minimize impact of the other uncontrolled factors to the results of an experiment. Randomization works best with larger groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Within-Subject Design&lt;/strong&gt;: A technique to see how a factor influences the impact we are measuring, for the same study subject, keeping other controlled and uncontrolled factors constant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>descriptive-statistics</category><guid>https://chowy1026.github.io/course-notes/descriptive-statistics/lesson-1/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 13:10:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Descriptive Statistics - Lesson 2</title><link>https://chowy1026.github.io/course-notes/descriptive-statistics/lesson-2/</link><dc:creator>cHoWy</dc:creator><description>&lt;h3&gt;Lesson 2: Visualizing Data&lt;/h3&gt;</description><category>descriptive-statistics</category><guid>https://chowy1026.github.io/course-notes/descriptive-statistics/lesson-2/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 13:04:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>https://chowy1026.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link><dc:creator>cHoWy</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello! I am &lt;!--\\[ e^{i\pi} + 1 = 0 \\] --&gt;writing this post &lt;!--\\( e^{i\pi} + 1 = 0 \\) --&gt; we'll see how this works!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--\\[ e^{i\pi} + 1 = 0 \\]--&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>hello-world</category><guid>https://chowy1026.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 13:36:10 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>