<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title> =^..^= MEH (plum_blossom_tree)</title><link>https://chowy1026.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="https://chowy1026.github.io/tags/plum_blossom_tree.xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 02:54:01 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Being Oblivious</title><link>https://chowy1026.github.io/posts/plum_blossom_tree/</link><dc:creator>cHoWy</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A random story.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one of the trips I went home, I was cleaning my parents' house and noticed a framed painting of plum blossom tree left laying flat on a nightstand.  It is a gift from my eldest nephew for my dad's birthday.  The drawing was quite well painted, and I felt it's such a shame to let it lay flat.  So, I decided to hang it up.  I spent a couple moments admiring it after I did that, cause I was quite impressed by my nephew's painting.&lt;br&gt;
A couple days later, my brother, the painter nephew's dad, came visit.  He too noticed the painting was hung up.  He asked "who hung the painting".  I proudly and promptly said "I did.".  "I couldn't stand letting it lay flat on a nightstand," I added.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He then said, "You've hung the picture upside down."  Then he spent 15 min conversation on how to tell the correct orientation of the painting by looking at the twigs in the painting.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was totally embarrassed, but was grateful that my brother corrected my mistake.  It also reminded me how oblivious I am about the little (good) things that I take for granted.  I have completely forgotten that a plant, or a tree, big or small, their twigs and branches always grow up, even sometimes extending sideways.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was hanging the painting up, I was thinking "Luckily my nephew did see his painting just left laying around, it would have broken his heart."  Now, I wonder, would he be more upset to see the painting laying around or to see the painting was hung upside down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>oblivious</category><category>painting</category><category>plum_blossom_tree</category><guid>https://chowy1026.github.io/posts/plum_blossom_tree/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 02:08:32 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>